<amProjectDB xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="file:/C:/mdcs/ammd/1.5/installer-pkg/data/schema/am_schema_R2018a.xsd">
    <amProject>
        <projectID>NIST-IN625-RR-14</projectID>
        <projectName>Interlaboratory study for nickel alloy 625 made by laser powder bed fusion additive manufacturing to assess mechanical property variability</projectName>
        <projectDescription>This round robin study has three goals. The first goal is to refine the AM test protocols and analysis methods to improve our process of 
            conducting a RR study. Secondly, we wanted to assess the variability in the tensile properties of Inconel 625 tension specimens from different institutions. 
            IN625 was chosen for this study because it is an inexpensive metal commonly used in the AM community. The last goal was to take another step towards being 
            capable of carrying out extensive round robin tests that will result in certification of AM materials.             
            This project to refine the methods for conducting RR studies for AM processes is part of a NIST program objective to accelerate the use of AM parts in
            high performance applications in the US and part of a NIST developed roadmap for advancing AM (ref NIST roadmap). With an established RR method, studies 
            can then be conducted to provide data to an AM material’s database.
            The focus of this study was to assess the variability in laser powder bed fusion (LPBF) 
            machines. Three different LPBF machines were used; 5 were Delta MU200 machines , 1 was an Delta MU300 machine, and 1 was an SLM 250. The intent of the study was
            that all the AM machines would fabricate identical builds. However, because of differences in machine manufacturers (Delta versus SLM) and even models of 
            the same manufacturer (MU200 versus MU300) some settings were different. Participants with the same machines also had different levels of control to modify 
            machine settings based on their purchased access and software version. There were 7 participants in the study, and each participant used only one AM machine.
            Two participants were academic institutions, two were commercial companies, and 3 were government institutions</projectDescription>
        <organization>NIST</organization>
        <start>2014-01-01</start>
        <end>2015-12-31</end>
        <contact>Christopher Brown</contact>
    </amProject>   
</amProjectDB>
